RYAN MACEACHERN

Software Developer

CONTACT

778.587.3982

ryan.maceachern.tech@gmail.com

In LinkedIn.com/in/Rmaceac

https://github.com/Rmaceac

Victoria, BC, Canada

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript Rubv

HTML CSS

Python **Typescript**

SQL

Frameworks/Libraries

NodeJS

Three.js

React

EJS

Rails

FRB

jQuery

Bootstrap

Ajax

SASS

Express.js

Testing

Storybook

Jest

Cypress

Mocha

Chai

Capybara

Rspec

Systems & Databases

Git + GitHub

PostgreSQL

Firebase

GraphQL

Audio + Visual

Blender

Figma

Lightroom

Da Vinci Resolve

Reaper

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with a background in adventure tourism and finance. I am excited to use my extensive experience in customer service to understand users' challenges and desires in the apps that I develop. I love working in collaborative teams that prioritize educational functions of apps and accessibility of information.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT DIPLOMA

Lighthouse Labs April 2022

ADVENTURE GUIDE DIPLOMA

Thompson Rivers University 2012 - 2014

PROJECTS

Seek A daily geolocation game where users test their geography knowledge by guessing the restaurant and allow SMS

location of unique street-view images. Players can connect with their other players,

compare scores and create their own custom games to share with their friends.

Front-End: ReactJS, SCSS Back-End: NodeJS, Express,

SQL, Postgres

Spuddies Food-Ordering

An Javascript application for customers to place orders with a communication between owner and customer regarding the status of the order (using Twilio's API).

Scheduler

A scheduler app where the user can create, edit and delete interview appointments.

Front-End: HTML, SCSS Back-End: NodeJS, Express, SQL,

Postgres

Front-End: ReactJS, SCSS Back-End: NodeJS, Express, SQL Testing: Jest, Storybook, Cypress

WORK EXPERIENCE

OWNER/OPERATOR

Blue Sky Bookkeeping – Self-Employed | 2017 - Present

- Working with clients from a dozen different industries to translate what matters most to them and ensure their values are prioritized in the communication and organization of their business finance.
- Recently saved a client over \$7,000 in PST charges using my attention to detail to make amendments to their sales tax filings.

HR LEAD & OPERATIONS COORDINATOR

Maple Leaf Adventures | 2019 - 2020

- Filled multiple, extremely dynamic roles that required regular, thoughtful communication with a crew of 50+ employees, ship's crew, engineers and many other employees/clients, each with a different set of values and priorities.
- Spearheaded the company's training sponsorship program in conjunction with WorkBC's Employer Training Grant, processing employee applications and writing grants for a variety of programs.

LEAD KAYAK GUIDE

One Ocean Expeditions | 2018 - 2019

- Led groups of ~15 guests with a small team of assistant guides through remote locations on the Antarctic Peninsula while managing safety, logistical and customer experience operations on board the expedition ship
- Regularly made consequential judgement calls that prioritized the safety of my team and guests, while also providing an incredible experience for our clients.